Benson Arafat

BACKEND ENGINEER

Abuja, Nigeria | (234) 8172681841

benpaul320@gmail.com bensonarafat.com linkedin.com/in/realArafatBen

SUMMARY

Accomplished professional software engineer with 4 years of expertise in strategic collaboration and creative thinking. Previous accomplishments include increasing the coding efficiency of e-commerce businesses by 80% and helping to boost client retention by 70%. A powerful point for uncovering growing technologies and dedicated to company growth and improvements.

SKILLS

• PHP

JavaScript

HTML

Flutter

VueJs

Laravel

REST API

CSS

OOP

Android Studio

MYSQL

Git

Dart

PostgreSQL

JQuery

EXPERIENCE

Jubilee System LTD – Wuse Zone 3, Abuja, Nigeria

Backend Engineer, September 2021 – Present

- Managed a process re-engineering project to improve and consolidate end-to-end service processes; restructured communication flow among 10 departments and cut down paperwork by 75%.
- Produced and updated website to facilitate 1000 daily visitors.
- Refined and upgrade existing software to continuously improve performance by 50%.
- Reduced bugs reported by 99% which contributed to customer satisfaction and reduction of customer complaints or support calls.
- Determined job priorities for up to 5 projects simultaneously and reviewed information regularly on websites and pages to ensure 100% accuracy.

Estasom – Jabi Abuja, Nigeria

Backend Engineer, February 2021 – September 2021

- Liaised with buyers and sellers to complete transactions worth over \$9,633.
- Worked effectively in a team of 6, developing new fundraising projects to drive increased funding and drove strategic efforts that boosted metal sales by 50% and overall sales by 17%.
- Coordinated evaluations making the best use of available budget and resources.
- Maintained understanding of current web technologies and programming practices through continuing education and participation in professional conferences and workshops.
- Wrote supporting code for web applications and websites.

GuageConcepts – Remote

Full Stack Engineer, February 2021 – June 2021

- Reviewed information regularly on websites and pages to ensure 100% accuracy.
- Constructed reusable code that could be utilised in other projects, saving company \$1,000.
- Analysed user needs to determine technical requirements.
- Spearheaded production of page content such as visuals and text copy to meet project specifications and built user interface, data visualizations and designed overall user experience, resulting in 20% increase in sales.

Bemo Technologies – Gaduwa Abuja, Nigeria

Full Stack Engineer, April 2019 – February 2021

- Developed applications that were successfully downloaded by 1000 + users.
- Collaborated with marketing teams to effectively promote applications, increasing app sales by 100% within the first 5 days of product release.
- Built applications bringing in \$1200 within the first month of release, exceeding manager expectations.
- Managed fleet of 20 vehicles, planning routes and timings to maximize adherence to schedule.
- Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks.
- Took concepts and produced design mock-ups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve site interactions.

EDUCATION

National Open University of Nigeria – Abuja, Nigeria B.sc Computer Science 2019 – 2022

Auchi Polytechnic Auchi – Edo State, Nigeria National Diploma Computer Science 2014 – 2017